Welcome!
欢迎光临
How about some hot fried chicken?
要不要参考一下刚出炉的炸鸡？
Please touch your phone there!
请在这边感应
DRAW ONE COUPON FOR EVERY PURCHASE OVER 700!!
（结账金额满700圆可抽一次）
By the way, sir…
那么这位客人
We're having a special campaign!
这是目前举办的抽奖活动
Please draw a coupon.
请抽一张吧
Wait…
难不成…
Will you go to the convenience store tomorrow?
明天会去超商吗？会去吧？
-You will right? -Is this the reason…
-你为了让我抽奖 -来我打工的店吧
Why you were so insistent last night?
昨天才会那么唠叨…
Why not?
有什么关系？
It's on your way home from school
你放学后也很顺路
and you buy dinner at the convenience store, anyway.
反正你每天都会在超商买东西吧？
I guess.
的确是啦
I haven't seen you since the festival.
校庆之后就没见了
Is Runa doing well?
瑠奈过得好吗？
Yes.
很好
She seems to be studying hard.
她很认真在读书的样子
I see.
这样啊
She calls me occasionally,
她偶尔会打给我
but I don't see her in person lately.
但没什么机会见面啊
Oh my, is this a friend of yours?
哎呀，是你的朋友吗？
Ms. Shinohara!
篠原女士
He certainly is handsome.
他长得真帅耶
That's right.
是啊
We met through an online video game.
我们是因为玩游戏认识的
Such a beautiful face…
长相好端正哦
He could be an actor.
简直像演员一样
I'll be going, now--
那我先走了…
I'll be done soon. Wait for me!
我就快下班了，等我一下
Let's go home together!
我们一起回去吧
He's waiting for you like a real gentleman.
他很乖地在等你下班哦
Don't tell me he's your boyfriend?
难不成是你的男友？
No, he's not.
才不是啦
He's uncomfortable around girls,
他好像蛮怕女生
so it's not like that.
我们不是那种关系
Oh, that's a waste.
讨厌，真遗憾
Still, you like him, don't you?
不过小茜你喜欢他，对吧？
You tried really hard to keep him here.
看你那么拼命地留下他
Uh…
这个嘛
I wonder…
谁知道呢？
Oh, what an innocent response!
真是的，好少女的回答
It's true that compared to when we first met,
和刚认识的时候相比
Yamada's a lot more accepting of me now.
现在山田对我确实变得坦率多了
In fact, I get the feeling…
“他其实是个很温柔的男生”
You must be tired.
辛苦了
…that he's a really nice guy.
我有时也会这么想
Thanks for waiting!
久等了
We only met on an online game,
虽然原本只是游戏网友
so it makes me happy to know we can become closer.
能像这样变得亲近，让我好开心
But that goes
但是这样的说法…
for Eita and Runa too, right?
也能套用在瑛太和瑠奈身上吧
I didn't invite you just for the coupon.
我不是为了抽奖活动才找你啦
The truth is…
其实
I made you lunch to say thanks.
我做了便当给你，想聊表心意
I wanted to give it to you.
所以才会叫你来
Thanks for what?
心意？
For my computer.
修笔电的回礼
I had no chance to thank you, because of the festival.
因为校庆时没机会致谢
It never bothered me.
不用回礼也没关系啊
I've finally broken free of my money worries,
最近我的手头终于宽裕多了
so it's a pretty luxurious meal.
这次的菜色很豪华哦
I don't really know why,
虽然我也不晓得为什么
but I get the feeling I shouldn't look at him
但我总觉得不能把山田
as a love interest.
当作恋爱对象…
Oh no, I sneezed in front of someone preparing for exams.
糟糕，在考生面前打喷嚏了
Do you have a cold?
你感冒了吗？
I wonder…
我也不知道
Did I bring a mask?
我有带口罩在身上吗？
Find one?
有找到吗？
Yes.
有了
I hope your cold doesn't get worse.
希望你的症状不会变严重
Yeah.
嗯
Thanks.
谢谢你
Men who are kind without realizing it
会无意识流露温柔的男人
can be terrifying, don't you think?
你不觉得可怕吗？
Go on.
你继续说
If you're not careful,
一旦松懈下来
you could even start to feel
“奇怪？他该不会喜欢我吧？”
that they have a crush on you.
会不小心产生错觉
But in fact, it's nothing like that.
但本人完全没那个意思
He's just naturally kind.
只是默默在发挥贴心本性
It's a terrifying trap.
是个可怕的陷阱
I have one question.
我想先确认一点
How are you so sure that there's no chance?
为什么你敢说对方没那个意思？
Oh, and can I make your nails a little flashy?
还有我能画得华丽一点吗？
"Butterfly of the night" style.
主题是“夜之蝶”
Don't. I'll get in trouble at work.
别那样，打工时会被骂
You haven't said who you're talking about,
虽然你完全没提到主词
but I know it's Yamada.
但八成是在说山田吧？
I mean,
没错
you were happy when he called you an unattainable flower, right?
他说你高不可攀，你不是还很高兴？
I'm sure that had no deeper meaning, either.
就连那句话应该也毫无深意
That's why he's so terrifying.
所以我才说他可怕
Even if it were a slip of the tongue, if a hot younger man
要是有比我小的帅哥一时昏头
said something like that to me,
对我说出那样的话
I'd pounce on him right away.
小桃我绝对立刻展开攻势
I don't know why you're hesitating.
我不懂你在扭捏什么
It's not hesitation.
我才没在扭捏
Oh?
是吗？
I feel like this is the most hesitant I've ever seen you.
在我看来是茜史上最扭捏的一次
You enjoy talking about Yamada
你总是喜孜孜地聊山田的事
and you've been probing his feelings,
试图确认他的心意
but you haven't told me anything about what you want.
却完全不表示自己有什么打算
Until you do,
如果你不说出来
there's not much else I can say.
我也不好发表意见
You're right.
所言甚是
-Butterflies of the night! -I said no.
-夜之蝶！ -我拒绝
RUNA SASAKI CALLING
（佐佐木瑠奈来电）
Oh, it's Runa.
是瑠奈
Oh, her?
那个女孩？
I remember. The junior-high Lolita girl.
我还记得，就是萝莉装初中生
Yeah, her.
没错，喂？
Akane, can you meet me right away?!
茜！现在可以见面吗？
It's a guild emergency!
这是公会的一大事件！
Runa!
瑠奈
Sorry to keep you waiting!
让你久等了
Should you be walking alone at this time of night?
你可以在这种时间独自出门吗？
It's already getting dark.
天色已经开始暗了哦
It's fine. I came by taxi.
瑠奈搭出租车来，没差
I'll go home by taxi too.
回去时也会搭出租车
Well, that's a relief.
那我就放心了
Oh, get this.
听我说
I ran into Yamada this afternoon--
其实我白天见到山田…
Did you even read my text?!
话说！你看了瑠奈的简讯吗？
Oh, yeah.
有啊
I read it.
我看了啊
A new member will enter the guild, huh?
说是公会有新成员加入…
Another unknown woman has joined.
又有不认识的女生加入公会了
I can't believe this!
难以置信！
In the beginning, Eita said he would keep it between us!
明明之前说自己人一起玩就够了
I mean, I like you now, Akane.
人家现在很喜欢茜哦
She's so territorial…
-可是这样下去 -有够排斥外人…
But at this rate,
等大考结束，瑠奈回锅时
it'll be a whole new guild soon!
公会就已经完全变样了
Plus, I don't like being around other girls!
还是女的！瑠奈最不会应付了！
They always end up hating me!
女生总是会马上讨厌瑠奈
I'm excited, myself.
我倒是很期待啊
I hope it's a woman who doesn't know much about video games.
希望是不太熟悉在线游戏的女生
I bought cocoa. Want some?
我买了可可亚，要喝吗？
You're too carefree!
太悠哉了！
So with that in mind…
综上所述
I quickly developed a plan to drive her away.
赶走新成员的计划已经写好了
Bad girl!
住手！
Newbies are always nervous,
新手容易感到不安
so we have to give them a good welcome.
我们要懂得好好欢迎对方哦
Plus, if you get to know them,
而且只要认真交流
you might even become friends.
说不定就能成为好朋友
Like you and I did.
就像我和瑠奈一样
When I imagine becoming friends with someone I wouldn't normally meet,
一想到能和平常没交集的人当朋友
I get a bit excited.
就会觉得有点兴奋耶
That's why I'm against it!
所以瑠奈才讨厌
You'll just become friends with the new girl right away!
到时候你一定会和对方变得很要好
Then you'll start hanging around with her more than me!
然后比起瑠奈更常和那个女生玩
That's not true.
才不会那样
I've never spoken to her--
我也还没和她说过话…
Well, it'll happen!
绝对会变成那样！
Can't we all just get along?
三人一起当朋友就好啦
No! No odd numbers!
瑠奈讨厌奇数！
Someone will be left out!
一定会多一个人啊
Let's all be friends.
大家一起好好相处吧
Okay?
好吗？
It's like I've got a jealous girlfriend.
像交了一个很爱嫉妒的女友
I knew…
茜说的那些话
you'd say that.
瑠奈其实也懂
My brother did too.
哥哥也是
The new girl was introduced by Yamada,
他说这次的人是山田介绍的
so he said I have to welcome her.
要我们好好欢迎对方
By Yamada?
山田介绍的？
It's a girl from his class.
听说是他班上的女生
I've heard she used to only play FPS games,
平常好像都在打FPS类型的游戏
but she wants to try MMO as a change of pace.
说是想玩MMO转换心情
They're supposedly close.
他们感觉蛮要好的
When I asked what she was like, over the phone…
就算瑠奈在电话里逼问细节…
Tell me!
快告诉我！
She's a regular person.
就是个普通人
Yamada wouldn't tell me anything.
山田都不太肯说
But he said if I did anything like I did to you,
还说要是跟茜那时候一样恶作剧
that he'd be really mad.
他真的会发脾气
A girl he's close to?
要好的女生…
It's unusual that
感觉还蛮意外耶
Yamada is introducing a girl to us…
山田竟然会介绍女生进来
You're right.
的确是啦
Actually, I have a great idea!
话说瑠奈想到一个好点子了
Give me your phone!
手机拿出来！
YAMADA
（联络人姓名，增加照片）
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I'm adding Yamada's phone number.
我在输入山田的手机号码
You should try calling him!
你打电话过去问问看吧
He didn't trust me,
现在他对瑠奈有戒心
but if you ask, he might tell you more!
但如果是你，或许他会愿意说
If I know what she's like,
先知道是什么样的人
it'll be a relief for me.
瑠奈也会比较安心
CRAM SCHOOL
（河井补习班）
-After that, they went straight to dating. -For real?
-然后他们似乎就顺势交往了 -真的假的？
Didn't they both say the other wasn't their type?
他们不是说对方都不是自己的菜？
That may be, but they're still man and woman.
说是这么说啦，但毕竟是一男一女
Even if it seems unlikely,
就算原本觉得没有可能
the smallest thing can bring them together.
有时候因为一点小事，就会在一起了
Can love really begin
男女朋友
from the smallest things?
会因为一点小事就交往吗？
Hey there, Class President.
班长，哈啰
Good evening, Okamoto and Yamada…
冈本同学，山田同学，你们好
Hi.
你好
Say, Ms. President…
话说班长
Talking to yourself is a funny way to make an entrance.
看你边走边自言自语，真好玩耶
Um, I was asking you two a question.
我刚才是在问你们
Love, huh…
男女朋友啊
How can I put it…
该怎么说？
Aren't we the wrong people to ask?
就算问我们也无解啊
You have a point.
也是
That reminds me, Yamada-kun.
对了，山田同学
Thanks for the guild introduction.
公会的事谢谢你了
You talked to the Master, right?
-特地帮我和会长牵线 -不会
What's she talking about?
你们在说什么？
Gaming.
是游戏的事
Oh, FOS?
FOS吗？
I started playing recently.
我最近开始玩
They say it's best to be in a strong guild,
但好像加入强一点的公会比较有利
so I had Yamada-kun introduce me to his.
山田同学就介绍我加入他们公会
That's right, you're a secret gamer.
班长是个隐性电玩迷嘛
I don't hide it or anything.
我也没在隐藏
It's just that I can't talk about gaming with other girls.
只是跟女生不会谈到这种事
All they talk about is romance.
她们都爱聊恋爱话题
Are you interested in romance, Ms. President?
班长对恋爱话题有兴趣吗？
Not really.
没兴趣
So you're another one who's dedicating their life to gaming.
班长也是把青春奉献给游戏的人啊
You're not gonna answer?
你不接吗？
It's an unknown number
是不认识的号码
and the class is about to start.
而且就快上课了
INCOMING CALL
（来电中）
Oh, they hung up.
挂掉了
You sure get a lot of calls like that, Yamada.
感觉山田很多这种电话
I'll bet when you answer, it's some girl asking you out.
一接起来，有陌生女生突然告白
If you ever wanted to, you could--
要是你有心，随时都可…
Yamada-kun
山田同学他…
isn't into things like romance, right?
对恋爱那种事不在行吧
SHE STARTLED ME
（突然那么大声 吓我一跳）
Well, not really.
是啊，倒是没错
That's what I thought.
我想也是
I'm hungry!
好饿哦
I'm gonna die of starvation.
我不行了，要死了
Didn't you just eat a hamburger?
你刚才不是才吃过汉堡？
A hamburger sounds good.
好想吃汉堡
Again?
又吃？
I know, I'll get some fries.
好，这次还要加薯条
Huh? Hey, are you listening?
奇怪？你有在听我说吗？
I have a phone call.
我打个电话
The same number as before?
回拨刚才的电话吗？
If it's a girl with a cute voice,
如果是个声音可爱的女生
then put me on!
就把电话交给我
Are you ignoring me?
不理我？
AKITO YAMADA CALLING
（山田秋斗来电）
Coming!
来了…
Hello?
喂？
Oh, excuse me, I--
不好意思，刚才…
Yamada?
山田？
It's me, Akane!
是我，我是茜
Akane?
茜？
It really was a woman.
真的是女生
Wait, did I tell you my--
奇怪？你有我的电话？
I know, right?
你果然很纳闷吧
Sorry about that.
抱歉，擅自打给你
The truth is that I was with Runa earlier tonight, and…
其实我傍晚跟瑠奈见了面…
Are you okay?
没事吧？
I'm fine. Anyway, there's something I wanted to ask you,
虽然我有事情想要问你
but I have to go to work now.
但我现在得去打工了
Didn't you already work?
可是你白天也…
It seems they can't get a hold of the person who's on the night shift,
店长好像联络不到晚班的人
so they called me in suddenly.
就突然叫我去救火
Isn't there anyone else?
没人可以代班吗？
Apparently not.
似乎没人的样子
Since I live close by, I'm an easy choice.
因为我住得近，找我比较方便
Yeah?
这样啊
You know, Yamada…
山田你…
He has a deep voice on the phone.
电话里的声音比较低沉
Oh, nothing!
没事了
WAITING FOR OKAMOTO
（冈本在买东西）
Was the person who called
刚才电话里的人
the one from the festival?
是来校庆的那个人？
How did you know?
你竟然猜得出来
I heard you call her name.
我记得你有叫她的名字
She's in our guild on FOS.
她也在我们的公会里
You'll get to know her too, Tsubaki.
到时候你应该也会碰到她
I see.
这样啊
You all get along well offline too, huh?
你们私底下也很熟耶
I suppose.
是啊
The Guild Master is my neighborhood senpai.
会长原本就是我的学长…
I can't recall…
她的脸…
her face…
我想不起来
What are they like?
是什么样的人？
Ei-- You mean the Guild Master?
瑛…你说会长吗？
No, this Akane person.
不是，我说那个叫茜的人
Akane…
茜…
My ex-boyfriend…
我的前男友啦
Is this a one-night stand?
一时意乱情迷犯了错？
Yamada!
山田！
SHE'S ALWAYS MAKING FUNNY FACES…
（总是露出怪表情…）
She's hard to describe.
我也不太清楚
Does that mean…
你该不会…
you like her?
喜欢她吗？
Akane!
小茜
Sorry, you're a life-saver!
抱歉哦，你真的救了我
I can't get a hold of the person on night shift
现在联络不上晚班的人
and it's impossible to handle everything myself.
只有我一个会忙不过来
Whoever the culprit is,
那种翘班惯犯
you had better fire them.
该炒他鱿鱼了吧？
Right…
也是啦
But they're a hard person to dislike.
但他不是讨人厌的家伙啊
They love the guitar and…
而且喜欢弹吉他
Uh, how about I buy you dinner?
我请你吃饭表示歉意吧
Would tomorrow night be okay?
明天晚上有空吗？
-I know a good-- -Not a chance!
-我知道好吃的餐厅… -不去！
I'LL EAT AT HOME.
（我会在家自己吃饭）
With this cold coming on, I wanted to go to bed early.
因为有点感冒，我本来还想早点睡
CALL HISTORY AKITO YAMADA, MOMO, MOMO, MOMO
（通话纪录）
It feels strange to see Yamada's name in my call history.
通话纪录里有山田，真是奇妙
Anyway, let's get to work!
好啦，上工吧
You haven't told me anything about what you want.
你完全不表示自己有什么打算
Akane!
小茜
Coming!
来了
Get it together!
糟糕…
WILL YOU LOG INTO THE ARERA 5 SERVER?
（要登入亚莉亚第5服务器吗？）
PLAYER: PRINCESS RURI HAS INVITED YOU TO JOIN THE CHOCOLATE RABBIT GUILD. JOIN?
（收到瑠璃姬的公会邀请 要加入吗？）
FOR ALL THOSE WITH BROKEN HEARTS
（《失恋良药》《送给失恋的你》）
I don't miss him anymore,
虽然我对他没有留恋
but these days, there are some things…
但是事到如今…
Forgive me, Akane.
茜，抱歉
…that I regret.
有一件事让我觉得后悔
AKANE CALLING
（茜来电）
It's Akane!
是茜打来的
-Can I answer? -Go ahead.
-可以接吗？ -请便
What's up, Akane?
茜，怎么啦？
I'm in the middle of my lesson.
瑠奈我在上家教课
Runa…
瑠奈…
What's with that scary voice?!
那是什么声音？好扯！
A cold?
感冒？
So then, no gaming today?
那今天原本说好上线…
I see.
这样啊
It's okay. I understand.
没关系，这也没办法
Take care!
要保重哦
Akane has a cold.
茜说她感冒了
She sounded on the verge of death.
声音听起来好像快挂了
I wonder if she's okay.
不晓得有没有事
I hope it's not serious.
希望不严重
COOLING PADS
（退热贴）
My throat is so sore,
喉咙太痛了
I can't even drink water.
水吞不下去
But I have to take some medicine.
我必须吃药才行
PRETTY SEVERE SYMPTOMS
（蛮严重的）
And I need to eat something too.
但在那之前，必须吃点什么
I haven't eaten since yesterday.
我从昨天就什么都没吃
Let's take a quick break.
稍微休息一下
QUICK BREAK
（暂时停机）
I feel awful.
好痛苦
And talk about bad timing…
而且偏偏在这种时候
CLINIC CLOSED ON SATURDAYS AND HOLIDAYS
（小柳医院，六日及假日休诊）
I really…
感觉好像…
The number you are calling is unavailable…
您拨的电话无人接听
have no luck…
诸事不顺
Even so…
可是…
I can't just feel sorry for myself.
就算唉声叹气
No one is going to come to my aid.
也没人会来救我
If I don't act on my own,
如果自己不动
death is the only alternative.
只有死路一条
First, food…
首先是吃饭
Maybe rice porridge?
要做点粥之类的
Gotta go to the store…
必须去买东西
I have no rice.
家里没米了
Forget the bus.
别搭公交车好了
I'll just infect others.
会散播病毒的
That's right. I have my bike.
对了，可以骑自行车
Okay…
很好
At least my brain is working.
脑袋还转得过来
I just have to… get through the night, somehow.
希望我能靠毅力撑过今晚
I can't ride a bike right now!
我骑不了自行车
It's out of the question!
完全不行
I'm burning up…
好热
Wait, couldn't I just order out?
话说叫外卖就行了吧？
Why didn't I think of that before?
我为什么没注意到？
Yeah. There's delivery.
对啊，有外卖嘛
Good thinking.
我真聪明
But first…
在那之前
I have to stand my bike back up.
我要扶好自行车
Then, I'll go back to my room and…
然后再回到家里…
What was I gonna do, again?
接着要做什么？
My head hurts.
头好痛
Akane…
茜
What's going on?
怎么回事？
That almost looks like Yamada.
我似乎看到像山田的人
But then…
但是
there's no way he's at my apartment.
他不可能会在我家啊
Can you hear me?
听得到我说话吗？
Is this a dream?
是梦？
Oh, man…
不妙啊
I'm even seeing him in my dreams now.
竟然连梦里也出现他了
I'm sorry, Yamada.
山田，抱歉哦
For including you in my dreams like this…
擅自做这种图利自己的美梦
Butterfly, butterfly
蝴蝶啊
Land on…
在我身上
Me!
停驻吧！
I'm Momoko Maeda, Butterfly of the Night.
我是夜之蝶，前田桃子
Tonight, the prince I've searched for
我命中注定的王子
will be--
今晚一定要找到…
GIRL WITH GLASSES SOOTHING TYPE
（眼镜妹，疗愈型）
THE BUTTERFLY OF THE NIGHT WITHERS
（夜之蝶惨败）
Excuse me! I need another.
不好意思，这再来一杯
Go strong on the gin.
琴酒要烈一点
Momo isn't answering…
小桃都不接电话